I showed you how to call functions in
我向您展示了如何使用call方法调用另一个合约中的函数
another contract using the call method
but it's not the best way to call other
但这不是调用其他函数的最佳方法，所以我想向您展示一个更好的方法
functions so I want to show you a better
way of calling functions that are in
调用另一个合约中的函数的方式，所以我将向您展示如何
another contract so I'll show you how to
call functions in another contract and
另一个合约中的调用函数以及如何将eater发送到应付款函数
how to send eater to a payable function
first we're gonna need a contract that's
首先，我们需要一份要被调用的合同，所以我要命名为
gonna get called so I'm gonna name this
contract Collie and we'll declare some
合约Collie，我们将在此示例中声明一些状态变量，
state variables for this example the
state variable value will be used when
当我们将Eater发送到此合同和
we send eater to this contract and to
show you an example of how to call a
向您展示了如何从另一个合约中调用常规函数的示例
regular function from another contract
we're first going to declare a function
我们首先要声明一个名为set X的函数，该函数将一个单位作为
called set X that's gonna take a unit as
input we will declare the function as
输入后，我们会将函数声明为public，并向您展示如何分配
public and to show you how to assign the
output of this function in the contract
合同中该函数的输出，在这里调用该函数
that call this function here we're gonna
return a new int inside the function
在函数内部返回一个新的int会简单地重新分配状态变量
will simply reassign the state variable
X to the employee and then we turn the
X给员工，然后我们将状态变量X的值作为输出
value of the state variable X as output
next to show you an example of how to
接下来向您展示如何调用应付款功能的示例，这意味着
call payable function which means that
the function can receive either we're
该函数可以接收我们将首先创建的函数
gonna first create a function like the
function above set accents and a third
上面的重音符号的功能，而第三个功能将使您不再
function is going to take a you ain't as
input and since this function is going
输入，并且由于此功能将能够接收它，我们需要
to be able to receive it we need to
declare as payable and for this example
声明为应付款项，在此示例中，我们将返回多个输出，并且它们
we'll return multiple outputs and they
don't I'll show you how to assign
我不告诉你如何从多个输出分配变量并且相同
variables from multiple outputs and same
as the function above you'll assign the
作为上面的函数，您将状态变量X分配给输入，并且因为
state variable X to the input and since
we're gonna send it to this function
我们将其发送到此函数将捕获加热器中的值
will capture the value of the heater in
the state variable value and then return
状态变量值，然后返回状态变量X的值，
the value of the state variable X and
value so that completes the code for the
值，从而完成合同的代码，这将被称为
contract and that's gonna get called
next we need a contract that's gonna
接下来，我们需要一个合同，该合同将被称为上述合同的呼叫，
call the call the contract above and
we'll name this contract caller we will
我们将命名此合同调用方，稍后将在集合X中命名此函数
name this function as set X later after
we deploy the contracts you'll call this
我们部署您将从中调用此功能的合同
function from
account and this function will call the
帐户，此函数将调用牧羊犬内部的set X函数
set X function inside the collie
contract above to call the functions in
上面的合同来调用牧羊犬合同中的功能，我们首先需要
the collie contract we first need to
pass the collie contract as input now
现在，当我们实际调用此函数时，将牧羊犬合同作为输入传递
when we actually call this function what
we need to pass here as input is the
我们需要通过此处，因为输入是此处牧羊犬合同的地址
address of the collie contract in here
we're saying that the type for the first
我们是说第一个输入的类型是牧羊犬合约和
input is the collie contract and the
valuable name for this input is called e
此输入的有价值的名称称为e，接下来我们将传递youant作为
and next we'll pass in a youant as the
second input so how do we call the set X
第二个输入，那么我们如何调用牧羊犬内部的set X函数
function which is inside the collie
contract well it's pretty
合同很好，这很简单，您可以打电话给我们
straightforward and you can call the set
X function which is inside the collie
像这样的牧羊犬函数内部的X函数，您将传递
function like this and you'll pass the
input X now if this syntax are passing
如果此语法正在传递合同，则现在输入X，因为输入似乎令人困惑
the contract as input seems confusing
you can do it like this instead instead
您可以这样操作，而不是通过合同作为输入，您可以
of passing the contract as input you can
pass the address of the contract as
通过合同的地址作为输入，您可以实例化
input and you can instantiate the
contract at the address like this here
合同在这样的地址在这里我们实例化合同
we're instantiating the contract at the
address where we got the address of the
从我们声明的输入中获取合同地址的地址
contract from the input we'll declare
the variable name as collie and the type
变量名称为牧羊犬，变量类型为牧羊犬合约
of the variable is the collie contract
so that's how you instantiate a contract
这样便可以从地址实例化合同，然后调用函数
from address and you can call functions
on the contract in the exact same way as
按照与上面示例完全相同的方式进行合同处理，所以这两个是
the example above so these are the two
ways of calling a function in another
在另一个合同中调用函数的方法，所以接下来我想向您展示
contract so next I want to show you how
to call a payable function and send
调用一个付费功能并与之一起发送我将调用此功能
either with it I'll call this function
set X and Sandy tur and like the example
设置X和Sandy tur，就像示例Bob一样，将需要调用合同
Bob it's gonna take to call the contract
as the first input and you'll pass a
作为第一个输入，您将为第二个输入传递一个youant，因为
youant for the second input and since
we're going to send it to this function
我们将其发送到此函数将声明为应付款，因此我们已经
will declare as payable so we already
know how to call function in another
知道如何在另一个合约中调用函数，所以我将复制此示例
contract so I'm gonna copy this example
as our starting point and instead of
作为我们的起点，而不是在
calling the set X function in the
colleague contract we're going to call
同事合同，我们将其称为集合X时态，
the set X tense and
either function and your pasta input X
任一功能和您的面食输入X并向该功能发送食用者
and to send eater to this function you
can do it like this you write and don't
可以像这样写，不用在想要的功能之后赋值
value after the function that you want
to call here I want to forward although
在这里打电话，我想转发，尽管发送到此功能的食者
the eater that was sent to this function
so inside the parentheses that come
因此，在值方法后面的括号内，我要通过
after the value method I'm gonna pass
message dot value which means that we're
消息点值，这意味着我们将转发所有的食者
gonna forward all of the eater that was
sent to this function and since the set
发送到此函数，并且由于在内部设置了X和食砂盘函数
X and sand eater function inside the
call the contract returns two outputs
调用合同返回两个输出，我们需要将代码更新为
here we need to update our code to
assign variables for two outputs since
为该函数分配两个输出，因为该函数将返回两个
the function is going to return two
outputs we first need to start with
我们首先需要以括号开头的输出，第一个输出是a
parentheses the first output is a you
end so we will declare a variable of
结束，所以我们将声明一个类型为U的变量，第二个输出也是
type U and the second output is also all
you end so we will declare the second
您结束了，所以我们也将第二个变量声明为youant，以便
variable as youant as well so that
completes our code let's now deploy the
完成我们的代码，现在让我们部署合同
contracts
so here I've deployed the Collie and the
所以在这里，我已经部署了Collie和color contract，对于第一个示例
color contract and for the first example
I'm gonna call the function set X which
我要称它为函数集X，当我们称它为函数集X时
is here when we call this function it
should call the set X function inside
应该在同事合同内部和内部调用set X函数
the colleague contract and inside the
Cloe contract it's gonna call this
Cloe合约将调用此函数并设置状态变量X
function and set the state variable X
which we'll check later so I'm gonna
我们稍后再检查，以便我复制通话D合同的地址
copy the address of the call D contract
and then pass it as the first input and
然后将其作为第一个输入传递，然后对于第二个输入，我将传递
then for the second input I'll pass in
the number of one two three and to check
一二三的数量，并检查是否一切顺利，我们将检查
that everything went through we'll check
the value of the state variable X and
状态变量X的值，并且在调用合约内，它是
inside the call the contract and it's
one two three
一二三接下来我要给你看一个
next I'm going to show you a
demonstration of set X and send eater
集X的演示并在此处发送Eater函数，所以当我们称其为
function here so when we call this
function inside the caller contract it's
调用者合约内部的函数，它将在内部调用相同的函数
going to call the same function inside
the Colie contract and inside the kaga
Colie合约和kaga合约中将设定状态
contract it's gonna set the state
variable x and the amount of ether that
变量x和
was
and again I'm gonna copy the address of
然后我要复制牧羊犬合同的地址粘贴到这里，
the collie contract paste it in here and
this time you'll pass the input four
这次您将通过输入四五六，我们将发送一米，所以现在
five six and we'll send one meter so now
when we check back on the state valuable
当我们检查状态X的值时，现在是4 5 6，其值是
X it is now four five six and the value
that was sent should be one either so I
发送的应该是一个，所以我只是向您展示了如何在
just showed you how to call functions in
another contract and this is the better
另一个合同，与使用合同相比，这是更好的方法
way of doing it compared to using the
call method why is that so well recall
调用方法为什么这么好回想一下，您将使用调用方法
that using the call method you would do
something like test to call the function
例如test之类的调用函数集X并将其发送的东西，您将通过
set X and send it you would passing the
function signature of the function that
您要调用的函数的函数签名，然后是输入
you're gonna call followed by the input
and if this function does not exist then
如果此函数不存在，则call方法将调用后备
the call method will call the fallback
function now the advantage of calling a
函数现在调用这样的函数的优点是，如果
function like this is that if the
function does not exist then literally
函数不存在，那么从字面上看，您将不会进行编译，例如，如果我
you will not compile so for example if I
change the name of the function
更改函数名称，然后按ctrl进行编译
and then hit ctrl s to compile you'll
notice that it did not compile so by
请注意，它没有通过使用此调用函数的方法进行编译
using this method of calling functions
in another contract you can check for
在另一份合同中，您可以在合同平整之前检查是否存在错误
errors before the contract is even
deployed and before we go I want to warn
部署，在我们出发之前，我想警告您一些您应该做的事情
you about something that you should be
aware of what do you think will happen
知道当我们调用函数集X时您会怎么想
when we call the function set X and
passing the address of a contract that
传递例如不是联系人的合同的地址
is not the call the contact for example
instead of passing the address of the
而不是通过同事合同的地址，而是通过地址
colleague contract we pass the address
of this contract foo well surprisingly
这个合约foo非常令人惊讶，这里的编码方会称其为
the coding side here will call this
function when we passing the address of
当我们传递食物的地址作为输入而不执行
food as input instead of executing the
code inside here inside the colleague
同事合同里面的代码让我给你看一个例子
contract let me show you an example so
here I deployed the color and the food
在这里，我部署了颜色和食物合同，当我们将集合x称为
contracts and when we call the set x
function passing in the address
在传递食品合同地址的功能中，您会注意到
the food contract you'll notice that the
cold inside the food contract was
食品合同中的合同被执行了，所以我通过了他们一二三
executed so I passed them one two three
as input the code inside the contract
作为输入，执行了合同foo内部的代码，并实现了一个
foo was executed and it implemented one
two three by one and we got one two four
二三一一，这里得到一二四
here so when we call this function and
passed in the address of foo instead of
传入foo的地址，而不是在此处执行此代码，而是执行了
executing this code here it executed the
code here inside the full-contact so
完整联系方式中的代码，因此请记住，您签订的合同
keep in mind that the contract that you
think you're calling might not be the
认为您所打电话的可能不是所称的实际合同，因此
actual contract that is being called so
in some way you can call functions in
以某种方式，您可以在另一个合约中调用函数，类似于您的调用方式
another contract similar to how you call
functions in object-oriented programming
面向对象编程中的函数，这比使用调用更好
and this is better than using the call
function to call functions in another
函数调用另一个合同中的函数，因为如果函数没有
contract since if the function does not
exist then solidity will not compile
存在，那么坚固性将无法编译，而使用call方法它将
whereas using the call method it would
just call the fallback function and you
只需调用后备功能，您将无法捕获错误，直到
won't be able to catch your error until
you deploy the contract and actually
您部署合同并实际执行功能并牢记
execute the functions and keep in mind
that the contract that you think you're
您认为您正在呼叫的合同可能不是实际的合同
calling might not be the actual contract
that is being called if you have any
如果您有任何反馈或问题，请在电话中告诉我
feedback or questions let me know in the
comments below have a good night
以下评论祝您晚安